The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Today's our last lecture
教授：今天是我们的最后一次演讲
on dynamic programming, the grand finale.
动态编程方面的盛大结局。
And we have a bunch of fun examples today on piano,
今天我们在钢琴上有很多有趣的例子，
guitar, Tetris and Super Mario Brothers.
吉他，俄罗斯方块和超级马里奥兄弟。
What could be better?
有什么更好的办法吗？
We are, again, going to follow this five-step plan
我们将再次遵循这一五步计划
to dynamic programming, define sub-problems, guess something
动态编程，定义子问题，猜测
in order to solve a sub-problem, write a recurrence that
为了解决一个子问题，写一个递归
uses that guessing to relate different sub-problems,
使用该猜测来关联不同的子问题，
then build your dynamic programming either
然后构建您的动态编程
by just implementing as a recursive algorithm
通过仅实现为递归算法
and memorizing or building it bottom up.
并自下而上地记忆或建立。
For the first, you need to check with the recurrence is acyclic.
首先，您需要检查循环是否非周期性。
For the second, you need an actual topological order.
第二，您需要一个实际的拓扑顺序。
These are, of course, equivalent constraints.
这些当然是等效的约束。
Personally, I like to write down on topological order
就个人而言，我喜欢写下拓扑顺序
because that proves to me that it is acyclic,
因为这向我证明了它是非循环的，
if I think about it.
如果我考虑一下。
But either way is fine.
但是任何一种方式都可以。
Then we get that the total running time
然后我们得出总运行时间
is number of sub-problems times time per sub-problems,
是子问题数乘以每个子问题的时间，
and then we need to solve our original problem.
然后我们需要解决我们原来的问题。
Usually it's just one of the sub-problems,
通常这只是子问题之一，
but sometimes we have to look at a few of them.
但有时我们必须看看其中一些。
So that's what we're going to do.
这就是我们要做的。
And we have one new concept today
今天我们有了一个新概念
that all these examples will illustrate,
所有这些例子都将说明
which is a kind of second kind of guessing.
这是第二种猜测。
We've talked about guessing in part two
我们已经在第二部分讨论过猜测
here in which we saw the obvious thing.
在这里，我们看到了明显的东西。
In the recurrence, we usually take the min
在复发中，我们通常会服用
of a bunch of options or the max of a bunch of options.
一堆选项或一堆选项的最大值。
And those options correspond to a guessed feature.
这些选项对应于一个猜测的功能。
We don't know whether the go left or go right,
我们不知道向左走还是向右走
so we try them both.
所以我们都尝试
That's guessing.
那是猜测。
But there's another way to guess.
但是还有另一种猜测的方式。
So two kinds of guessing.
因此有两种猜测。
So you can do it in step two.
因此，您可以在第二步中进行操作。
Let's see what I have to say about these.
让我们看看我要说些什么。
In step two and three, you are guessing usually
在第二和第三步中，您通常会猜测
which sub-problems to use in order
按顺序使用哪些子问题
to solve your bigger sub-problem.
解决更大的子问题。
So that's what we've seen many, many times by now.
因此，这就是我们到目前为止已经看到很多次了。
Every DP that we've covered except for Fibonacci numbers
除斐波那契数外，我们涵盖的所有DP
has used this kind of guessing.
使用了这种猜测。
And it's sort of the most common, I guess you might say.
我想您可能会说这是最常见的。
But there's a higher level of guessing
但是猜测的水平更高
that you can use, which we've sort of seen
您可以使用的，我们已经看到了
in the knapsack dynamic programming, dynamic program,
在背包动态编程，动态程序中，
which is when you define your sub-problems, you can add more.
在定义子问题时，可以添加更多问题。
Add more sub-problems to guess or you can think of it
添加更多子问题进行猜测，或者您可以考虑一下
as remembering more features of the solution.
记住该解决方案的更多功能。
And we just leave it at that.
而我们只剩下它了。
Essentially what this does-- so remember with knapsack,
本质上是这样做的-请记住背包，
we had a sequence of items.
我们有一系列物品。
They had values and sizes.
他们具有价值和规模。
And we had some target knapsack, some capacity.
我们有一些目标背包，一些容量。
We wanted to pack those items into that knapsack.
我们想将那些物品装进那个背包。
And the obvious sub-problems were suffixes of the items.
并且明显的子问题是项目的后缀。
Because we always know suffixes, prefixes, substrings,
因为我们一直都知道后缀，前缀，子字符串，
those are the obvious things to try.
这些都是显而易见的尝试。
But suffixes wasn't quite enough.
但是后缀还不够。
Because if we looked at a suffix,
因为如果我们看一下后缀，
we didn't know of the prefix that we've
我们不知道我们拥有的前缀
skipped over how many of those items
跳过了其中的几项
were in-- and in particular, how much of the capacity
尤其是多少容量
we'd used up.
我们用光了。
And so we needed to add more sub-problems
因此，我们需要添加更多子问题
to remember how much capacity had we used up in the prefix.
记住前缀中已经用完了多少容量。
We did that by multiplying every sub-problem
我们通过乘以每个子问题来做到这一点
by s different choices, which is how many units of the knapsack
通过不同的选择，即背包的单位数
still remain.
仍然保持。
So in some sense, we're remembering more
所以从某种意义上讲，我们还记得更多
about the prefix.
关于前缀。
You can also think of it as-- in the more forward direction,
您也可以将其视为-在更向前的方向上，
we have the suffix problem.
我们有后缀问题。
I'm going to solve it s different times,
我要解决不同的时间，
or s plus 1 different times.
或s加1个不同的时间。
I'm going to solve it.
我要解决它。
What if I had a big knapsack?
如果我有一个大背包该怎么办？
What if I had a smaller knapsack?
如果我有一个较小的背包怎么办？
What if I had a zero-size knapsack?
如果我的背包尺寸为零，该怎么办？
All of those different versions of the problem.
所有这些问题的不同版本。
In some sense, you were solving more sub-problems.
从某种意义上说，您正在解决更多子问题。
You're, in some, sense finding more solutions
在某种意义上，您是在寻找更多解决方案
to that sub-problem.
这个子问题。
You're looking at a suffix.
您正在查看一个后缀。
And I want to know all these different solutions that
我想知道所有这些不同的解决方案
use different amounts of the knapsack.
使用不同数量的背包。
So in that sense, you're just adding more sub-problems.
因此，从这个意义上讲，您只是添加了更多子问题。
But from a guessing perspective, you're
但从猜测的角度来看，
remembering more about the past.
记得更多关于过去的事情。
We're going to see a bunch of examples of this type today.
今天，我们将看到大量此类示例。
We'll always use this type, but we'll
我们将始终使用此类型，但我们将
see more of this where the obvious sub-problems don't work
在明显的子问题不起作用的地方看到更多
and we need to add more.
并且我们需要添加更多。
So the first example is piano and guitar fingering.
所以第一个例子是钢琴和吉他指法。
This is a practical problem for any musicians in the audience.
对于听众中的任何音乐家来说，这都是一个实际问题。
How many people here play piano, or have played piano?
这里有多少人弹钢琴，或者曾经弹钢琴？
OK, about a quarter.
好，大约四分之一。
How many people have played guitar?
有多少人弹吉他？
A few, all right.
几个，好吧。
I brought my guitar.
我带了吉他。
I've been learning this semester.
这个学期我一直在学习。
I'm not very good yet, but we'll fool around
我还不是很好，但我们会鬼混
with it a little bit.
一点点。
So the general idea is you're given some musical piece
所以一般的想法是给你一些音乐作品
that you want to play.
你想玩的。
And on a piano, there's a bunch of keys.
在钢琴上，有一堆琴键。
You have all these keyboards, so you
您拥有所有这些键盘，所以您
know what a piano looks like, more or less.
或多或少知道钢琴是什么样子。
It's just like a keyboard, but only row.
它就像一个键盘，但只有一行。
It's crazy.
这很疯狂。
Each key that you press makes a note,
您按的每个键都会做一个音符，
and every key has a different note.
每个键都有不同的音符。
So it's very simple from a computer scientist's
因此，从计算机科学家的
perspective.
透视。
You want to play a note, you push the key.
要弹奏音符，请按该键。
But you could push it with any one of these fingers.
但是您可以用这些手指中的任何一根推动它。
Humans have 10 fingers.
人类有十根手指。
Most humans.
大多数人。
I guess a few have more.
我想还有更多。
But you want to know, which finger should I
但是你想知道，我应该用哪根手指
use to play each note?
用来演奏每个音符？
It may not seem like a big deal.
似乎没什么大不了的。
And if you're only playing one note, it's not a big deal.
而且，如果您只演奏一个音符，那没什么大不了的。
But if you're going to play a long sequence of notes,
但是，如果您要演奏很长的音符，
some transitions are easier than others.
有些过渡比其他过渡容易。
So let's say we're given a sequence of n notes
假设我们给了n个音符序列
we want to play.
我们想玩。
And we want to find a fingering for each note.
我们希望找到每个音符的指法。
So fingering, so let's say there are-- I'm
所以指法，可以说-我是
going to label the fingers on your hand, 1 up to f.
将要标记您手上的手指，直到1。
For humans, f is 5 or 10, depending
对于人类来说，f是5或10，具体取决于
on if you're doing one hand or two hand stuff.
如果您正在做一只手或两只手的东西。
I think to keep it simple, let's think about piano, right hand
我想保持简单，让我们考虑一下钢琴，右手
only, and just you're playing one note at the time, OK?
只是，而您当时正在演奏一个音符，好吗？
We're going to make it more complicated later.
稍后我们将使其变得更加复杂。
But let's just think of a note as being a single note.
但是，让我们仅将注释视为单个注释。
OK, or you can think of guitar, single note, left hand
好，或者您可以想到吉他，单音符，左手
is playing things.
在玩东西。
You want to assign one of these fingers to each node.
您想要将这些分支之一分配给每个节点。
And then you have a difficulty measure, d.
然后，您便有了一个困难度量，d。
And this you need to think about for awhile
这需要您考虑一会儿
musically, or anatomically, how to define.
在音乐上或解剖学上如何定义。
If we have some note p and we're on finger f
如果我们有一些音符p并且在手指f上
and we want to transition to note q using figure g,
我们想使用图g转换为音符q，
how hard is that?
那有多难？
So this is-- the p and q are notes to play.
这就是-p和q是要演奏的音符。
I guess p stands for pitch.
我想p代表音高。
And f and g are fingers.
f和g是手指。
So this is how hard is it to transition from f on p
所以这就是从f到p过渡的难度。
to g on q.
到q上的g。
There's a huge literature on for piano.
钢琴方面有大量文献。
There are a lot of rules like, well,
有很多规则，例如，
if p is much smaller than q, unless they're stretched,
如果p比q小得多，除非它们被拉伸，
then that becomes hard.
然后就很难了。
And if you want to stretch, you probably
如果你想伸展，你可能
need to use fingers that are far away from each other.
需要使用彼此远离的手指。
If your playing legato-- so you have to smoothly go from one
如果您演奏连奏-那么您必须平稳地从一个开始
note the other-- you can't use the same finger on both keys.
请注意另一个-您不能在两个键上使用相同的手指。
So if f equals g and you're playing legato,
因此，如果f等于g并且您正在演奏连奏，
then p better be the same as q sort of thing.
那么p最好和q一样。
There's a weak finger rule.
手指法则很弱。
You tend to avoid fingers four and five, these two.
您倾向于避免手指四和五，这两个。
Apparently going from-- I'm not much of a pianist-- so
显然是因为-我不是钢琴家-所以
going from between three and four,
从三到四之间
which I can barely hold them up, it's kind of difficult,
我几乎不能忍受它们，这有点困难，
is "annoying."
是“烦人的”。
That's what I wrote down.
那就是我写下来的。
So between three and four transitions you try and avoid.
因此，请在三到四个过渡之间尝试避免。
And so you can encode into this function.
因此，您可以将其编码为该函数。
It's a giant table.
这是一张巨大的桌子。
You can just put in whatever values
您可以输入任何值
you want that you're most comfortable with.
您希望自己最满意。
And music theorists work a lot on trying
音乐理论家在尝试
to define these function so.
这样定义这些功能。
So you can do that.
这样就可以做到。
And for guitar, maybe I should do a little example.
对于吉他，也许我应该举个例子。
Get this out.
拿出来
I can't play much, so bear with me.
我不能玩太多，所以请忍受我。
Bet you didn't think this would happen in 006.
赌你没想到这会在006年发生。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
So let's see.
让我们来看看。
So let's say you're trying to play your favorite song.
假设您要播放自己喜欢的歌曲。
[STRUMS "SUPER MARIO BROTHERS"  THEME]
[STRONGS“ SUPER MARIO BROTHERS”主题]
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
OK.
好。
So when I'm playing that, I have to think about the fingering.
因此，当我演奏时，我必须考虑指法。
Which finger is going to go where to play each note?
哪个手指会去弹每个音符？
OK, so the first notes are actually open,
好，所以第一个音符实际上是打开的，
so it's really easy.
所以真的很容易
And then I go up to holding the first fret on the fifth string.
然后我将第五根弦上的第一个品格固定住。
OK, and I'm using my index finger because everyone
好，我正在使用食指，因为每个人
loves to use their index finger.
喜欢用食指。
And in particular because the very next note
特别是因为下一个音符
I'm going to play-- well, actually it's down here.
我要去玩-好吧，实际上它就在这里。
Then the next note is going to be this one.
那么下一个音符就是这个。
So I'm holding on the third fret of the bottom string.
所以我握住底部弦的第三个音格。
And then I've got to transition over here.
然后我必须在这里过渡。
And actually, usually I do it with my middle finger.
实际上，通常我用中指来做。
I don't know quite why I find that easier, but I do.
我不知道为什么我会发现这更容易，但是我知道。
OK, and so I've actually played that opening a zillion
好的，所以我实际上已经玩过
times with lots of different things.
时代有很多不同的东西。
This is the one I found to be the most comfortable.
这是我发现最舒适的一种。
And there's this issue, right?
还有这个问题，对不对？
If your pinky is here, where can I reach with this finger?
如果您的小指在这里，我可以用这个手指到达哪里？
Where can I reach with this finger?
用手指可以到达哪里？
It gets difficult.
很难。
And in particular, it's very hard for me
特别是对我来说很难
to reach down here when my pink is there.
当我的粉红色在那里时到达这里。
And so you can encode that in this d function
因此，您可以在此d函数中对其进行编码
however you want.
随你怎么便。
You get the idea.
你明白了。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
Thanks.
谢谢。
I'll skip to our lessons. [? We're ?] [? worth ?]
我将跳过我们的课程。 [？我们是？] [？值得吗？]
[? it. ?] So let's solve this with dynamic programming, OK?
[？它。 ？]那么让我们通过动态编程解决这个问题，好吗？
That's the cool thing.
那是很酷的事情。
So we can do it.
这样我们就可以做到。
And we follow our five step procedure.
并且我们遵循我们的五步过程。
So the first thing is to define sub-problems.
因此，第一件事就是定义子问题。
What are the sub-problems for a set-up like this?
这样的设置有哪些子问题？
What are the three obvious candidates?
三个明显的候选人是什么？
Do you remember last lecture?
你还记得上一次讲座吗？
How many people know the answer?
有多少人知道答案？
Just checking.
只是检查。
One person.
一个人。
Go for it.
去吧。
AUDIENCE: Prefixes, suffixes, and substrings.
听众：前缀，后缀和子字符串。
PROFESSOR: Right.
教授：对。
Prefixes, suffixes, and substrings.
前缀，后缀和子字符串。
We have a sequence of notes.
我们有一系列注释。
We're not going to worry about the sequence of fingers.
我们不会担心手指的顺序。
I don't think that's too big a deal.
我认为这没什么大不了的。
That's what we're finding.
这就是我们所发现的。
What we're given is a sequence of notes,
我们得到的是一系列注释，
so we should try suffixes, prefixes, or substrings.
因此，我们应该尝试后缀，前缀或子字符串。
I'll just tell you, suffixes are fine.
我只告诉你，后缀很好。
Kind of.
的种类。
So a sub-problem will be suffixes,
因此，子问题将是后缀，
so how to play notes from i onwards.
那么如何从i开始演奏音符。
Intuitively, we want to figure out,
凭直觉，我们想弄清楚，
how should we play the first note?
我们应该如何演奏第一音符？
And then we go on to the second note and so on.
然后，我们继续第二个音符，依此类推。
So we're applying them one by one
所以我们一一应用
from left to right from the prefix side.
从前缀一侧从左到右。
And so we'll always be left with a suffix.
因此，我们总是会留下一个后缀。
OK, then we need to guess something.
好的，那么我们需要猜测一下。
What's the obvious thing to guess,
有什么显而易见的猜测，
given I need to play notes i onward?
鉴于我需要继续弹奏笔记？
Think little harder.
多想一点。
This one you shouldn't have to think.
您不必思考这一点。
That's what I tell you.
我就是这么告诉你的
Try suffixes, try prefixes, try substrings.
尝试后缀，尝试前缀，尝试子字符串。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Maybe which finger to just put around i?
听众：也许我要戴哪根手指？
PROFESSOR: Yeah, which we're going to use for note i.
教授：是的，我们将在笔记i中使用它。
Our whole point is to assign fingering.
我们的重点是分配指法。
The first note here is i.
这里的第一个音符是i。
So let's think about i, what could you do for i?
那么，让我们考虑一下我，您能为我做什么？
We'll try all the possibilities.
我们将尝试所有可能性。
Which finger to use for note i?
我要用哪个手指做笔记？
OK, now the really hard part-- because it's impossible--
好吧，现在真正困难的部分-因为这是不可能的-
is to write a recurrence.
是写一个循环。
This is wrong, by the way, but it's the first thing to try.
顺便说一句，这是错误的，但这是尝试的第一件事。
So this is what I want to ask you
所以这就是我想问你的
to do because it's not possible.
之所以这样做，是因为不可能。
But intuitively, what we might try to do
但直觉上，我们可能会尝试做的
is we're trying to solve DP for i.
是我们正在尝试为我解决DP。
And we want to find-- this is difficulty,
我们想发现-这很困难，
so you want to minimize difficulty.
所以你想尽量减少难度。
So we'll take a min over all of our guesses
因此，我们将花一点时间讨论所有猜测
of what it would take to solve the rest of the notes,
解决其余笔记所需的时间，
to play the rest of the notes, plus somehow the cost
演奏其余的音符，再加上费用
of playing the first note.
演奏第一个音符。
So what's the cost of playing the first note?
那么演奏第一音符的费用是多少？
And then is going to be a for loop over fingers.
然后将成为手指之间的for循环。
OK, that's going to be the min.
好，那将是最小的。
We want to try all possible fingers for note i.
我们想尝试所有可能的手指作为注释i。
Then we have to play all the remaining notes.
然后，我们必须演奏所有剩余的音符。
And then there's this transition cost
然后有这个过渡成本
where you're going from note i to i plus 1.
从注释i到i加1的位置。
So it's going to be something like d
所以它将像d
of if-- we know that we use finger f to play i-- then
如果-我们知道我们用手指f演奏我-
we have to go to note i plus 1.
我们必须注意我加1。
But then the problem is we have no idea what to write here,
但是问题是我们不知道在这里写什么
because we don't know what finger we're
因为我们不知道我们是哪根手指
going to guess for note i plus 1.
我猜猜我加1。
So this cannot be known.
因此，这是未知的。
OK, but it's the first thing you should
好，但这是您应该做的第一件事
try, because often this works.
尝试一下，因为这经常有效。
For simple DPs, that's enough for sub-problems.
对于简单的DP，这足以解决子问题。
But we need to know more information
但是我们需要了解更多信息
about what we're going to do next.
关于我们接下来要做什么。
And this seems very worrisome, maybe
这似乎很令人担忧，也许
now we have to guess two things.
现在我们不得不猜测两件事。
Do we have to guess more than two things?
我们是否必须猜测两件事以上？
Turns out two things is enough.
事实证明，两件事就足够了。
But we cannot use this type of guessing.
但是我们不能使用这种猜测。
We need to use-- we need to add more sub-problems.
我们需要使用-我们需要添加更多子问题。
More sub-problem, more power.
更多子问题，更多功能。
So any guesses what we could do for sub-problem?
那么有什么猜想我们可以为子问题做什么？
A couple of right answers here.
这里有几个正确的答案。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Maybe like all the suffixes [INAUDIBLE]
听众：可能像所有后缀一样[听不清]
like the i, for all written i's, like all the possible fingers
就像我，对于所有书面我来说，就像所有可能的手指
for i?
为我？
PROFESSOR: All the possible fingers
教授：所有可能的手指
for i in the sub-problem.
对于我在子问题。
Yeah, good.
耶，好样的。
How to play-- it's still about the suffixes.
怎么玩-仍然是关于后缀的。
We're still going to use that.
我们仍将使用它。
But we're going to suppose we already
但是我们要假设我们已经
know what finger to use for the first note, note i.
知道第一个音符使用哪个手指，请注意i。
OK, this is a little weird, because we were guessing that
好吧，这有点奇怪，因为我们猜测
before.
之前。
Now we're just supposing someone tells
现在我们只是假设有人告诉
us, use finger f for that note.
我们，用手指f表示该音符。
This will work.
这将起作用。
That's the one I had in mind.
那就是我想到的那个。
But the question becomes, what should we guess?
但是问题变成了，我们应该猜什么？
Anyone else?
还有谁？
You clearly get [? a pillow. ?] I
你清楚得到[？一个枕头。 ？] 一世
don't know how many you have by now.
不知道你现在有多少。
Have another one.
再来一个
That's tough.
太难了
This is not easy to figure out.
这不容易弄清楚。
Now, given that that's our sub-problem, what
现在，考虑到这是我们的子问题，
is the next thing to guess?
接下来要猜测的是什么？
Do you have an idea?
你有想法吗？
AUDIENCE: I got an idea to define it.
听众：我有一个定义的想法。
Like either the next or previous finger for the--
就像食指的下一个或上一个
PROFESSOR: The next or previous finger.
教授：下一个或上一个手指。
Well, I'm looking at suffixes.
好吧，我在看后缀。
So I only care about the next one.
所以我只关心下一个。
Yeah.
是的
I see what you mean by next or previous.
我明白您的意思是下一个或上一个。
But what we mean is note i plus 1,
但是我们的意思是注意我加1
that's the next thing we don't know about.
那是我们不知道的下一件事。
So we're going to guess finger-- we'll
因此，我们将猜测手指-
call it g-- for note i plus 1.
称它为g--表示我加1。
And now magically, this recurrence
现在神奇的是，这种复发
becomes easy to write.
变得容易写。
So it's almost the same thing.
因此，几乎是同一回事。
I wish I could just copy and paste this over, but I can't.
我希望我可以将其复制并粘贴到上面，但不能。
It's not a digital blackboard.
它不是数字黑板。
Are there digital blackboards?
有数字黑板吗？
That would be cool.
那肯定很棒。
Someone should make that.
有人应该做到这一点。
I don't know why switched from open parens to square brackets,
我不知道为什么从开放括号改为方括号，
but I did.
但是我做到了
Then we have-- I think it's just the obvious thing, if i plus 1
然后我们有-如果我加1，我认为这只是显而易见的事情
g.
G。
Ahh, this is a slightly wrong, though.
嗯，不过这有点不对。
It's a copy paste error.
这是复制粘贴错误。
This should really be DP of i comma
这应该是我逗号的DP
f, because now sub-problem consists of two things-- which
f，因为现在子问题由两件事组成-
suffix am I in, and what's my finger for note I?
我在后缀中，请注意，我的手指是什么？
And so when I call DP, I also have to provide two arguments.
因此，当我调用DP时，我还必须提供两个参数。
It's going to be DP of i plus 1 comma g.
这将是DP的i加1逗号g。
And then I'm looping over g.
然后我遍历g。
I'm trying all possibilities for g.
我正在尝试g的所有可能性。
That's the recurrence.
这就是复发。
So if I want starting with finger f on note i,
因此，如果我想从音符i的手指f开始，
how do I solve the suffix from i?
我如何解决我的后缀？
Well, I guess what finger am I going
好吧，我猜我要去哪根手指
to use for the very next note.
用于下一个音符。
Then I have to pay this transition cost for f on i
然后我必须为我的f支付过渡费用
to g on i plus 1.
给我加1。
Yeah, OK.
是的，好的
So slightly, I'm cheating the notation here.
稍微说一下，我在这里欺骗这个符号。
This probably should be the note, what is note i,
这可能应该是注释，注释i是什么，
and this thing should be what is note i plus 1.
这个东西应该是我加1的注解
If you think of this d function just being given
如果你想到这个d函数
notes, pitches that you need to play,
音符，需要演奏的音调，
instead of indices into the array.
而不是索引到数组中。
It doesn't really matter, but that's how I defined it before.
其实并不重要，但这就是我之前定义的方式。
OK, so I have to pay this transition cost.
好的，因此我必须支付此过渡费用。
What does it take to make that transition from i to i plus 1?
从i过渡到i加1需要什么？
And then what does it take to do the rest of the notes, given
然后，给出给定的其余注释需要做什么
that now my finger is-- or now finger g is playing the note
现在我的手指是-或现在手指g正在演奏音符
i plus 1?
我加1？
So we transition from f to g, and that's now
所以我们从f过渡到g，现在
kept track of in the sub-problem.
跟踪子问题。
This is the magic of defining more sub-problem.
这是定义更多子问题的魔力。
We needed to know where our finger used to be.
我们需要知道我们的手指曾经在哪里。
And now we're telling it, oh, your finger right now
现在我们正在告诉它，哦，你的手指现在
is finger f.
是手指f。
Finger f is the one that's currently playing the note.
手指f是当前正在播放音符的手指。
And then afterwards, g is the finger that's currently
然后，g是当前的手指
playing the note, and we can keep track of that.
播放音符，我们可以对其进行跟踪。
You could also define this to say, oh,
您也可以将其定义为，哦，
f was the finger that was used for the previous note,
f是用于上一个音符的手指，
note i minus 1.
注意我减1。
But it's just a shifting of the indices here.
但这只是索引的变化。
You can do i minus 1 to i instead of i to i plus 1.
您可以对我减去1，而不对我加1。
But this is, I think, slightly cleaner.
但是，我认为这稍微清洁一些。
OK, and then we have a DP, right?
好，然后我们有DP，对吗？
We've just memoized that recurrence.
我们刚刚记下了这种复发。
We get a recursive DP, or you could build it bottom up.
我们获得了递归DP，或者您可以自底向上构建它。
If you were building it bottom up,
如果您是自底向上构建它，
you'd want to know a topological order.
您想知道拓扑顺序。
And this requires a little bit of care
这需要一点点的照顾
because there's two parameters.
因为有两个参数。
And so it's going to be a for loop
所以这将是一个for循环
over those two parameters in some order.
以某种顺序覆盖这两个参数。
And I believe the right order is for i
我相信正确的顺序适合我
has to go from right to left because this is suffixes.
必须从右向左移动，因为这是后缀。
So I would write reversed range n python if there are n notes.
因此，如果有n个注释，我会写反向范围n python。
And then within that loop, I would do a for loop over f.
然后在该循​​环中，我将对f进行for循环。
If you reverse the order of these for loops,
如果您颠倒这些for循环的顺序，
it would not be in the right order, I'm pretty sure.
我敢肯定，它的顺序不正确。
But this one will work.
但这将起作用。
You can check it.
您可以检查一下。
And then to solve our original problem, here
然后解决我们原来的问题
we require a little more work because none
我们需要做更多的工作，因为没有
of these sub-problems are what we
这些子问题是我们
want to solve because we don't know what the first finger is.
想要解决，因为我们不知道第一指是什么。
We know what the first note is.
我们知道第一个音符是什么。
That's note 0.
注释为0。
But what finger goes there?
但是什么手指去了？
I don't know.
我不知道。
And DP of 0 requires us to give it a finger.
DP为0要求我们给它一个手指。
Give it the finger, ha.
给它手指，哈。
Give it the finger for whatever is the first note.
用手指指任何第一音符。
So this is pretty easy though.
因此，这很容易。
We just take a min over those choices.
我们只花一分钟的时间就这些选择。
Which finger should we give it?
我们应该给哪根手指？
That should do it.
那应该做。
So we don't know what finger to start with.
因此，我们不知道从哪个手指开始。
Just try them all, take the min.
只要尝试全部，花点时间。
This is just like the guessing that we did here,
就像我们在这里所做的猜测一样，
just a slightly simpler version.
只是稍微简单一点的版本。
There's no transition cost because there's no transition.
没有过渡成本，因为没有过渡。
We weren't anywhere before.
我们以前没去过。
Just what finger do you start with?
您从哪一根手指开始？
I don't care what finger I start with.
我不在乎我用什么手指开始。
It's how I transition from one note to the next that's hard.
这就是我很难从一个音符过渡到另一个音符的方法。
OK, done.
OK完成。
That's the DP.
那就是DP。
Now, if this is not obvious or not clear,
现在，如果这不明显或不清楚，
I think it's easier to think about it in the DAG form.
我认为以DAG形式考虑它更容易。
So let's draw all the sub problems.
因此，让我们画出所有子问题。
We have here a two dimensional matrix of sub-problems.
这里我们有一个子问题的二维矩阵。
We have the different suffixes on the one hand.
一方面，我们有不同的后缀。
So this is it, it stats a 9, goes to n minus 1.
就是这样，它统计为9，等于n减1。
And then in the other dimension, we
然后在另一个方面，我们
have what finger to use from 1 to f.
从1到f使用什么手指。
And so in each of these positions, there a note.
因此，在每个位置中都有一个注释。
There's a sub-problem.
有一个子问题。
Race.
种族。
I wanted to get five rows because there are five fingers.
我想得到五行，因为有五个手指。
And then our transitions basically
然后我们的过渡基本上
look-- if we're at finger one on this note,
看-如果我们在此音符上用手指指一指，
we can go to finger one on the next note.
我们可以在下一个音符上动动手指。
Or we can go, if we're not legato,
或者我们可以走了，如果我们没有连音，
or we can go to finger two on the next note,
或者我们可以在下一个音符上移至第二根手指，
or finger three or finger four or finger five.
或三指或四指或五指。
And then if we're starting with finger two,
然后，如果我们从第二根手指开始，
we could go to any one of these.
我们可以去任何一个。
So you get a complete bipartite graph,
这样就得到了一个完整的二部图，
which you usually draw like this.
你通常这样画
That is how graph theorists draw complete bipartite graphs.
图论家就是这样绘制完整的二部图的。
OK, but I tried to draw a little more explicitly here.
好的，但是我试图在这里画得更明确一些。
It's just any possible transition.
这是任何可能的过渡。
And for each of these, the point is
对于每个这些，关键是
you can compute the D cost, because you
您可以计算D成本，因为您
know what figure you were at.
知道你在做什么。
You know what finger you are going to
你知道你要用什么手指
and what note you're starting from
以及你从哪开始
and what note you're going to.
以及您要注意的事项。
Those are the four arguments you need for D.
这些是D所需的四个参数。
So you put those weights on, and then
所以你把那些重物放在上面，然后
you solve shortest paths on this DAG.
您可以在此DAG上解决最短路径。
And that is exactly what this DP is doing, OK?
这正是DP所做的，好吗？
Except there's no single source here,
除非这里没有单一来源，
which is kind of annoying.
这有点烦人。
And so you need to take this min over what's
因此，您需要花几分钟时间了解
the shortest path from here, what's the shortest
从这里最短的路径，最短的是什么
path from here, from here, from here, from here.
从这里开始，从这里开始，从这里开始，从这里开始。
Of course, you don't actually need
当然，您实际上并不需要
to do that by running single source shortest paths f times.
为此，请运行单个源最短路径f次。
If you're a clever shortest paths person,
如果您是聪明的最短路径人，
you would add an extra source note, connect
您将添加一个额外的原始注释，然后连接
that with 0 weight to all of these sources.
所有这些来源的权重均为0。
So put 0s on there.
因此，将0放在那。
And then do single shortest paths from here.
然后从这里开始最短的路径。
And you will find the best way.
您将找到最好的方法。
You don't really care where you started,
你真的不在乎你从哪里开始
so this is trying all the options.
所以这正在尝试所有选项。
That's exactly what we're doing here.
这正是我们在这里所做的。
But here I'm doing it with the shortest paths trick,
但是在这里我用最短的路径把戏
here I'm doing it with guessing and taking a min like DP style.
在这里，我通过猜测并像DP风格一样花了一点时间。
OK, so that's how to do piano figuring and guitar
好，这就是做钢琴造型和吉他的方法
fingering for single hand, one note at time.
一只手的指法，一次注一次。
Questions?
有什么问题吗
And this even worse for aliens if you
对于外星人来说，甚至更糟
have arbitrarily many fingers on your hand.
手上有很多手指。
I guess we should figure out what's the running time.
我想我们应该弄清楚几点了。
So we have sub-problems.
因此，我们有子问题。
We see how many sub-problems there are here.
我们看到这里有多少个子问题。
There's n times f sub-problems.
有n次f个子问题。
How much time, or how many choices are there
多少时间，或有多少选择
for our guess?
为我们的猜测？
Well there's f different choices for what finger we use.
那么，我们使用哪种手指有f个不同的选择。
And when we do this min, we spend theta F time.
而当我们做这个分钟时，我们会花费theF时间。
Because there's a for loop over F,
因为在F上有一个for循环，
we're doing constant work assuming
我们一直在假设
D lookups take constant time.
D查找需要固定的时间。
This is theta F time.
这是θF时间。
So we multiply those two things together,
因此，我们将这两件事相乘，
and we get the total time, the number of sub-problems which
然后我们得到总时间，子问题的数量
is n times F, and we multiply them
是F的n倍，我们将它们相乘
by theta F for each sub-problem.
对于每个子问题，用θF表示。
So this is nF squared.
因此，这是nF平方。
And given F is usually pretty small, it's almost linear time.
鉴于F通常很小，几乎是线性时间。
So that's a pretty good algorithm.
因此，这是一个非常好的算法。
But in reality, you tend to play multiple notes
但实际上，您倾向于演奏多个音符
at the same time.
与此同时。
In music, typically you're playing a chord.
在音乐中，通常您正在演奏和弦。
With piano, you're playing several notes
使用钢琴，您会演奏几个音符
with one hand, maybe several notes with another hand.
一只手，也许另一只手有几个音符。
Two handed piano, it's crazy.
两只手的钢琴，这太疯狂了。
You could do four handed piano, make it a little more exciting.
您可以做四手钢琴，使它更加令人兴奋。
With the guitar, play-- I don't know very many chords,
用吉他弹奏，我不知道很多和弦，
but I know at least one.
但我至少知道一个
You play, I don't know.
你玩，我不知道。
This looks like something.
这看起来像东西。
That's a G chord.
那是G弦。
Do I know any others?
我认识其他人吗？
And that's an E chord.
那是E和弦。
All right, you get the idea.
好吧，您知道了。
I mean, for each of these chords,
我的意思是，对于每个和弦，
different people use different fingers,
不同的人用不同的手指，
even for a single cord.
即使是单根电线。
So it's sort of a personal taste how
所以有点个人品味
you're going to define your difficulty measure.
您将定义难度指标。
But I could play an E like this, or I could-- I don't know,
但是我可以像这样演奏E，或者我可以-我不知道，
play it like this.
像这样玩。
Or I could play like this.
或者我可以这样玩。
And there's lots of crazy ways to put your finger here
还有很多疯狂的方法可以将手指放在这里
and your finger here and your finger here.
和你的手指在这里，你的手指在这里。
And for each of them, you could define some difficulty.
而对于每个人，您都可以定义一些难度。
And then, of course, is a transition
然后，当然是过渡
from one chord to another.
从一个和弦到另一个。
And because there's different ways to play different chords,
而且由于演奏和弦的方式不同，
that wasn't a very good example because they all
那不是一个很好的例子，因为它们都
look pretty bad.
看起来很糟糕。
Well, this one for example, this is the G again.
好，例如，这是G。
I could use my-- one, two, three, four-- fourth finger
我可以用我的-，1、2、3、4-第四根手指
here, or I could use my fifth finger.
在这里，或者我可以用无名指。
My instructor says we should use our pinky because people
我的老师说我们应该使用小指，因为人们
tend not to use their pinky.
往往不使用其小指。
But it makes a difference what I'm
但这改变了我
going to transition to next.
过渡到下一个。
Maybe my pinky really needs to go over here next
也许我的小指下一步真的需要去这里
and I should free it up for later,
我应该释放它以便以后使用
or maybe it's better if this one's freed because then I
也许这是更好的，因为那我
can move it somewhere else.
可以将其移动到其他地方。
So that's what we'd like to capture
这就是我们想要捕捉的
in a generalized form or this dynamic program,
以一般形式或此动态程序，
and we can do it.
我们可以做到。
So I'll try to do it quickly so we
所以我会尽快做的，所以我们
can get on to the other examples.
可以继续看其他例子。
All right, other fun stuff.
好吧，其他有趣的东西。
Actually, there's another fun thing
其实还有一件有趣的事
with guitar, which is that there's
用吉他，那是
more than one way to play each note.
演奏每个音符的方法不止一种。
There are six strings here.
这里有六个琴弦。
And you could play like this note for the Super Mario
您可以像这样为超级马里奥演奏
Brothers.
兄弟。
I could also play that doing the fifth thing here.
我也可以在这里做第五件事。
It's slightly out of tune, but those sound almost the same.
有点不合时宜，但听起来几乎一样。
Or I could play on the 10th fret on the third string.
或者，我可以在第三弦的第十个品格上演奏。
That's the same as bottom one.
这与下一个相同。
So a lot of options, so you also like to capture that.
有很多选择，所以您也喜欢捕获它。
This is actually not too hard.
这实际上并不难。
You just need to generalize the notion of finger
您只需要概括一下手指的概念
to what finger you're using and what string you're using.
您正在使用的手指以及正在使用的字符串。
So there are f different choices for what finger you're using.
因此，您使用的手指有f个不同的选择。
If you use a generalized guitar, there's
如果您使用通用吉他，
s choices for what string you're playing.
选择要播放的字符串。
There's a lot of different guitars with various numbers
有很多不同数量的吉他
of strings, so we can just generalize that.
字符串，所以我们可以将其概括化。
And now it's not only, which finger am I going to use,
现在不仅是我要使用哪根手指，
but what sting will I play it on?
但是我会继续弹什么呢？
And then you can still define a difficulty measure
然后您仍然可以定义难度衡量
like this for this set up, depending
这样的设置，取决于
both on the finger and the string.
手指和弦上都有
And then the running time grows slightly.
然后运行时间会稍微增加。
It's now n times F squared S squared,
现在是F平方S平方的n倍，
because now I have to take the product of F and S. OK,
因为现在我必须取F和S的乘积。
so that's first thing.
所以这是第一件事。
But then if I wanted to do multiple notes,
但是如果我想做多个笔记，
well, you can imagine it's a similar type of deal.
好吧，您可以想象这是一种类似的交易。
It's going to get harder though.
但是，它将变得越来越困难。
First thing we need to generalize is the input.
我们需要概括的第一件事是输入。
Before the input was a sequence of notes.
在输入之前是一系列注释。
Now it's going to be a sequence of multi-notes.
现在将是一系列多音符。
So notes of i is now going to be, let's say,
所以我现在要成为一个音符，
a list of notes that all need to be played at once.
所有音符都需要同时演奏的音符列表。
And conveniently, it's probably going to be, at most, F notes,
而且方便起见，最多可能是F个音符，
because you really can only play one note with each finger
因为每个手指只能弹一个音符
pretty much.
差不多
I guess you could try to play two notes at once
我想您可以尝试同时演奏两个音符
on a piano with a finger, but eh.
用手指在钢琴上，但是
It sounds difficult.
听起来很难。
For a guitar, it's at most s notes.
对于吉他来说，最多是笔记。
You can only play one note per string, more or less.
每个字符串最多只能播放一个音符。
So that's our input.
这就是我们的投入。
And now we need to adjust the dynamic program.
现在我们需要调整动态程序。
And I think I'll tell you how to do this.
我想我会告诉你如何做到的。
Basically, now you need to know where all your fingers are.
基本上，现在您需要知道所有手指的位置。
So you go from one pose to another pose,
所以你从一个姿势转到另一个姿势，
from one chord to another.
从一个和弦到另一个。
Different ways to finger that.
用不同的方式来说明这一点。
Which fingers are and which strings
哪根手指是哪根弦
and which frets on the guitar, which fingers
吉他上有哪些烦恼，手指
are on which keys on the keyboard.
是键盘上的哪个键。
But you just need to know all that.
但是您只需要知道所有这些。
And all your fingers might be doing something,
而且你所有的手指可能正在做某事，
and you've got to know for each finger what note is it on,
而且您必须知道每个手指上都有什么音符，
or is it not being used at all.
还是根本不使用它。
So how many different ways to do such a mapping are there?
那么，有多少种不同的方法可以进行这种映射？
I mean, this is just a function.
我的意思是，这只是一个功能。
So it's the number of targets of the function.
这就是函数的目标数量。
So how many of these are there.
那么有多少个。
Gosh, well, I guess we said there are, at most, f notes.
天哪，嗯，我想我们说的最多是f个音符。
So f plus 1 is the maximum number of possible things
所以f加1是最大可能数
each finger can do.
每个手指都能做到。
And we raise that to the power of the number of fingers.
我们将其提高到手指数量的力量。
That's the possible mappings of what all of my fingers
那是我所有手指可能的映射
could be doing.
可能正在做。
It's exponential in f, not so great.
它在f中是指数的，不是很大。
But if f is 5, it's all right.
但是如果f为5，就可以了。
And then-- well, then you just generalize the rest.
然后-好吧，然后您就可以将其余的内容进行概括。
I don't think I'll write it down in detail.
我认为我不会详细记录下来。
But our sub-problems now are going
但是我们现在的子问题正在发展
to be-- let me switch boards here.
是的-让我在这里切换板子。
How do we play these multi-notes from i onwards,
我们如何从i开始播放这些多音符，
given that we're going to use that pose-- or I called
鉴于我们将使用该姿势-或者我打电话给
it the state of all my fingers-- for the first notes of i
这是我所有手指的状态-对于我的第一个音符
is now a whole bunch of notes.
现在是一堆笔记。
So given I'm now going to play those notes
因此，鉴于我现在要演奏这些音符
with this particular finger assignment,
通过这种特殊的手指分配，
how do I play the rest?
我怎么玩剩下的？
And then what we'll guess is the entire finger assignment
然后我们将猜测整个手指分配
for the next set of notes, i plus 1--
对于下一组音符，我加1--
the next chord, if you will.
下一个和弦（如果可以）。
And that guessing involves now F plus 1 to the F time.
现在猜测涉及F加F的时间1。
And then we just write the recurrence in the same way.
然后，我们以相同的方式编写重复记录。
So we're basically generalizing here we call the finger,
所以我们基本上在这里概括为手指，
now it's an entire pose for your hand.
现在这是您的整个姿势。
Instead of F, you might write H for hand or something.
您可以用H代替手写，而不是F。
And so the running time in this situation
因此在这种情况下的运行时间
is going to go up to something like n times F of plus
会上升到F的n倍
1 to the F. Did I miss anything?
1到F。我错过了什么吗？
Probably have to square that.
可能不得不平方。
2F.
2楼
Before it was F squared, now it's
在F平方之前，现在是
just F plus 1 to the F squared.
只是F加1到F的平方。
So if F is small, this is all right.
因此，如果F小，那么就可以了。
Otherwise, not so great.
否则，不会那么好。
This is the best algorithm I know for chord fingering.
这是我所知的和弦指法的最佳算法。
Questions?
有什么问题吗
Just trying to make it practical,
只是想使其实用，
solve the real life problem.
解决现实生活中的问题。
I would love, I think-- I don't know
我想，我想-我不知道
if this has been implemented, but someone
如果已经实施，但是有人
should implement this in some-- I don't know,
应该以某种方式实现这一点-我不知道，
score program, musical score program.
乐谱程序，乐谱程序。
I would love as learning guitar, it'd
我很想学习吉他，
be great for someone to just tell me how to finger things.
对某人来说很棒，只是告诉我如何去指责。
Then I can retroactively figure out
然后我可以追溯出
why using the dynamic program.
为什么使用动态程序。
All right, let's move on to Tetris.
好吧，让我们继续俄罗斯方块。
All these problems are going to have the same flavor.
所有这些问题将具有相同的味道。
You can solve them with basically
您基本上可以解决它们
the same dynamic program.
相同的动态程序。
It's all about figuring out what should the sub-problems be.
都是要弄清楚子问题应该是什么。
So let me-- does anyone here not know Tetris?
所以让我-这里有人不认识俄罗斯方块吗？
OK, good.
好好
No one's willing to admit it.
没有人愿意承认这一点。
So you've got these blocks falling.
因此，您已经跌落了这些障碍。
But I'm going to make several artificial constraints.
但是我要做出一些人为的约束。
First of all, I tell you the entire sequence
首先，我告诉你整个过程
of pieces that are going to come.
将要出现的碎片。
This is more like a Tetris puzzle.
这更像是俄罗斯方块难题。
OK, we're given sequence of n pieces that will fall.
好吧，我们得到了n个碎片的序列。
For each of them, we must drop the piece from the top.
对于每个人，我们都必须从顶部放下。
OK, and if you're a fancy Tetris player,
好的，如果您是俄罗斯方块玩家，
you can let a piece fall and then rotate it at very end
您可以放下一块然后在最后旋转
to do some clever, clever thing.
做一些聪明的事情
I disallow that.
我不允许。
You always have to push the drop button.
您始终必须按下下拉按钮。
So the piece starts here, it goes instantly to the ground.
因此，这部分从这里开始，立即到了地面。
This will be necessary.
这将是必要的。
I don't know how to solve the problem
我不知道该怎么解决
without this constraint.
没有这个限制。
OK, and then the other weird thing--
好吧，然后是另一件事
this is very weird for Tetris-- full rows normally clear,
对于俄罗斯方块来说这很奇怪-通常整行都很清晰，
but now they don't clear.
但是现在他们还不清楚。
This is like hardcore Tetris.
这就像铁杆俄罗斯方块。
You're guaranteed to die eventually.
你一定会死的。
The question is, can you survive these n pieces?
问题是，您可以在这n个零件中生存吗？
That's the question.
这就是问题所在。
Can you survive?
你能生存吗？
Oh, I've got one other constraint.
哦，我还有另一个约束。
This is actually kind of natural.
这实际上是自然的。
The width of the board is small, relatively small,
木板的宽度很小，比较小，
because we're going to be exponential in w.
因为我们将在w中取指数。
In real life it's 12, I think?
我认为现实生活中是12岁吗？
AUDIENCE: Ten.
听众：十。
PROFESSOR: Ten, sorry.
教授：十，对不起。
It's been a while since I wrote my Tetris paper.
自从我写《俄罗斯方块》论文以来已经有一段时间了。
So all right, these are all kind of weird constraints.
因此，这些都是怪异的约束。
If you don't make all of these constraints-- oh,
如果您不做所有这些限制-哦，
also the board is initially empty.
板子最初也是空的。
That's like level one of Tetris.
这就像俄罗斯方块的一级。
If all of these things are not the case, which
如果不是所有这些情况，那
is regular Tetris, if you just have the first thing
是普通的俄罗斯方块，如果您只有第一件事
then this problem is called NP-complete.
那么这个问题就叫做NP完全
We'll be defining that next class.
我们将定义下一个类。
So it's computationally intractable.
因此它在计算上很棘手。
But if you make all of these assumptions,
但是，如果您做出所有这些假设，
the problem becomes easy, and you
问题变得容易，而你
can do it by dynamic programming.
可以通过动态编程做到这一点。
So how do we do it?
那么我们该怎么做呢？
We define sub-problems just like before.
我们像以前一样定义子问题。
The obvious thing to try is suffixes.
显而易见的事情是后缀。
How do we play a suffix of pieces i onwards?
我该如何播放我以后的作品后缀？
How to play those guys.
怎么打那些家伙。
And just like fingering, this is not enough information, right?
就像指法一样，这还不够，对吗？
Because if we're going to play from pieces i onward, what
因为如果我要从头开始演奏，那
we need to now is what the board currently looks like.
我们现在需要的是董事会当前的样子。
I said here the board is initially empty.
我在这里说董事会最初是空的。
That's not going to be the case after you
在您之后情况将不再如此
place the very first piece.
放置第一块。
So in general, after we've placed the first i pieces,
所以总的来说，在我们放置了第一个i件之后，
we need to know what the board looks like.
我们需要知道董事会的样子。
And here's where I'm going to use all of these assumptions.
这就是我要使用所有这些假设的地方。
If you always drop things from the top and rows don't clear,
如果您总是从顶部放东西而行却不清除，
then all you really care about is how high each column is.
那么您真正关心的就是每列的高度。
This is what you might call the skyline of the board.
这就是您所说的董事会的天际线。
OK, now in reality, there might be holes here
好吧，现在实际上，这里可能会有漏洞
because you drop things in silly ways.
因为你以愚蠢的方式丢东西。
Maybe you drop a piece like this.
也许您放这样的一块。
And then I claim, because I'm dropping things
然后我声称，因为我要丢东西
from infinity from the sky, I really
从无边无际的天空，我真的
don't care about that there's a whole here.
不在乎这里有个整体。
I can just fill that in and say, OK, that's my new skyline.
我可以填写一下，然后说，好，那是我的新天际线。
Because if you can't do these last minute twists
因为如果你不能做这些最后的转折
and if lines never clear, that's going to be gone.
如果线条不清晰，那将消失。
That material is wasted.
那材料被浪费了。
OK, so all I need to remember is how high is each column.
好的，所以我需要记住的是每列的高度。
So I should say given the board skyline.
所以我应该说鉴于董事会的天际线。
Now, how many choices are there for that?
现在，有多少选择呢？
It's quite similar to this function, the fingering.
它非常类似于此功能，指法。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
There's the height of the board, different choices.
有板子的高度，有不同的选择。
It's going to be h.
将会是h。
For each column it could be anywhere between 0 and h,
对于每一列，它可以在0到h之间的任意位置，
so I guess h plus 1 if you want to get technical.
因此，如果您想获取技术知识，我想h加1。
And then we raise it to the power w,
然后我们将其提高到幂w
because there's w different columns and each of them
因为有w个不同的列，每个列
is independent choice.
是独立的选择。
So this is going to n times that different sub-problems.
因此，这将是不同子问题的n倍。
And here's what I need the is small
这就是我所需要的
because this is exponential in w.
因为这是w的指数
So it's reasonable in h, but exponential in w.
因此，它在h中是合理的，但在w中是指数的。
OK, then what do I guess?
好，那我猜怎么着？
Any suggestions what to guess?
有什么建议要猜吗？
AUDIENCE: So where the new piece falls, as in [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：那么新作品落在哪里，如[听不清]？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
What should I do with piece i?
我该怎么办？
There's not that many choices.
没有太多选择。
I can rotate it zero, one, two, or three times.
我可以将其旋转零，一，二或三次。
I can choose someplace to drop it,
我可以选择放一个地方
but those are my only choices.
但这是我唯一的选择。
So it's just how to play piece i.
因此，这就是如何演奏我的作品。
And given that guess, you can figure out
鉴于这种猜测，您可以找出
how the skyline updates, like I did here.
天际如何更新，就像我在这里所做的那样。
If I drop that piece like that, then I fill in this part
如果我那样掉那块，那么我要填写这部分
and recompute my new skyline.
并重新计算我的新天际线。
So it's going to be something like 4
所以大概是4
times w different choices, roughly-- 4 for the rotation,
w有不同的选择，大约-4表示旋转，
w for the x-coordinate.
w为x坐标。
And so the running time is just going
因此，运行时间即将过去
to be the product of these.
成为这些产品。
n times w times h plus 1 to the w.
n乘以w乘以h。
Open problem, if I drop any one of these assumptions,
公开的问题，如果我放弃这些假设中的任何一个，
can you get a dynamic program that's reasonable?
您可以获得合理的动态程序吗？
Could you do it if w is large?
如果w大，你能做到吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Could you do if rows do clear?
如果行清除，您能做吗？
That's the least natural constraint here.
这是最不自然的约束。
I don't know.
我不知道。
Puzzle for you to think about.
拼图让您思考。
I'd love to know the answer.
我很想知道答案。
You can obviously do the rest of the steps, right?
您显然可以完成其余步骤，对吗？
You can write down the recurrence.
您可以记下重复发生率。
It's the same thing.
这是同一件事。
You take the min over all guesses.
您将所有猜测都放在心上。
What are we minimizing?
我们要最小化什么？
Hmm.
嗯
I guess here the question is survival.
我想这里的问题是生存。
Can you survive?
你能生存吗？
So this is one of the first examples where the answer is
所以这是第一个例子，答案是
a Boolean value, true or false.
一个布尔值，真或假。
But if you think of true or false as 0 and 1,
但是，如果您认为true或false为0和1，
then it's still a maximization problem.
那仍然是一个最大化的问题。
You want to maximize.
您想最大化。
You want 1 if possible.
如果可能，您需要1。
Otherwise, you'll get 0 when you maximize.
否则，最大化时将获得0。
So you can write the recurrence using max.
因此，您可以使用max编写重复记录。
And in the base case, you have truth values, true or false.
在基本情况下，您将拥有真值（真或假）。
And you'll see, did I survive?
而且您会看到，我生存了吗？
Did I die?
我死了吗
That sort of thing.
之类的东西。
I want to go on to Super Mario Brothers,
我想去超级马里奥兄弟
because everyone loves Super Mario Brothers.
因为每个人都喜欢超级马里奥兄弟。
has?
拥有？
Anyone not played NES Super Mario Brothers 1?
没有人玩过NES Super Mario Brothers 1吗？
Aww, you got to play it, man.
噢，你一定要玩，伙计。
You're the only one.
你是唯一的一个。
You can play it on an emulator.
您可以在模拟器上播放它。
Maybe not legally, but you can play it on an emulator
也许不合法，但是您可以在模拟器上播放
and just see how it is.
看看情况如何。
So what I'm going to talk about next,
所以我接下来要谈的是
in theory, works for many different platform games,
从理论上讲，适用于许多不同的平台游戏，
side-scrolling platform games.
侧滚动平台游戏。
But Super Mario Brothers 1 has some nice features.
但是超级马里奥兄弟1具有一些不错的功能。
In particular, a nice feature is that whenever anything
特别是一个不错的功能是
moves off of the screen, it disappears from the world.
移动离开屏幕，它从世界上消失了。
So the monster moves off, it's gone.
所以怪物移开了，它消失了。
You can think of there's a static level there.
您可以想到那里有一个静态水平。
When the level comes into screen, when a monster comes
当关卡进入屏幕时，当怪物来时
on screen, then it starts acting.
在屏幕上，然后它开始起作用。
But as soon as you move the screen-- you can't actually
但是，只要您移动屏幕，您实际上就无法
move backwards in Super Mario 1, but as soon
在Super Mario 1中向后移动，但尽快
as you move forwards and that character is offscreen,
当您向前移动并且该角色不在屏幕上时，
it's gone.
它消失了。
So in a sense, that part of the level
所以从某种意义上说
reset to its initial state.
重置为其初始状态。
Now, as long as your screen is not too big-- and thankfully,
现在，只要您的屏幕不是太大-幸运的是，
on NES screens were not very big.
在NES屏幕上不是很大。
It's 320p, or whatever.
它是320p，或其他任何值。
This will work.
这将起作用。
If you are given the entire level--
如果您获得了整个级别的信息，
so let's say there's n bits of information there--
假设那里有n条信息
and you have a small screen, w by h screen, w and h
并且您有一个小屏幕，w和h屏幕，w和h
are not too big.
不太大。
Then I claim we can solve Super Mario
然后我声称我们可以解决超级马里奥
Brothers by dynamic programming.
兄弟们通过动态编程。
So let's say we want to maximize our score.
假设我们要最大化得分。
Want to run through the level and maximize your score,
想跑遍关卡并最大化您的分数，
or you want to minimize the amount of time you use.
或者您想减少使用时间。
You're doing level runs.
您正在执行关卡运行。
Pick your favorite measure, all of those can be solved.
选择您最喜欢的措施，所有这些都可以解决。
And the way to do it, this sort of general approach
以及这种方法，这种通用方法
to all these DPs is we need to write down
对于所有这些DP，我们需要写下来
what do I need to know about the game state.
我需要了解什么游戏状态。
I'll call that a configuration.
我将其称为配置。
What can we care about for Super Mario Brothers?
超级马里奥兄弟能为我们做什么？
Well, I guess everything on screen.
好吧，我猜屏幕上的所有内容。
This is a bit tricky, but there's stuff on screen.
这有点棘手，但是屏幕上有东西。
There are monsters and objects.
有怪物和物体。
For the monsters, I need to know their current position.
对于怪物，我需要知道它们的当前位置。
For the objects, I need to know-- like,
对于物体，我需要知道-
is there a question mark box?
有问号框吗？
Did I hit it already?
我已经打了吗？
Did I already get the coin or did I already get the mushroom?
我已经拿硬币还是蘑菇了？
So for each of those things, there's
因此，对于每件事，
some amount of information you need to store.
您需要存储一些信息。
How much information?
多少信息？
I think something like constant to the w times h should do.
我认为应该对w乘以常数。
That's saying for every pixel on the screen
也就是说屏幕上的每个像素
or for every square on the screen,
或屏幕上的每个方块，
however you-- whatever you define the resolution here
但是您-无论您在此处定义分辨率
to be.
成为。
Let's say for every little unit square in Mario land,
假设在马里奥（Mario）土地上的每个小单位广场，
is it a brick?
是砖头吗？
Is it a hard brick, or has it been a destroyed brick?
它是坚硬的砖块，还是被破坏的砖块？
Is a monster there right now?
现在有怪物吗？
Is Mario there right now?
马里奥现在在吗？
All these kinds of information.
所有这些信息。
OK, so there's a cost number of choices for each pixel.
好的，因此每个像素都有一个成本选择。
You can write them all down.
您可以将它们全部写下来。
You might also want Mario's velocity.
您可能还需要Mario的速度。
I had to play it again just to check
我只好再次检查一下
that there is indeed velocity.
确实有速度。
Turning around is slower than going forward.
转身比前进慢。
You do accelerate a little bit.
您确实会加速一点。
So you've got to remember that.
因此，您必须记住这一点。
There's probably only a constant number
可能只有一个常数
of choices for what your velocity is.
速度的选择。
What else?
还有什么？
Ah, I want to remember the score.
啊，我想记住分数。
You want to maximize score.
您想最大化分数。
And let's say you also-- how much time is left.
再说一遍，您还剩下多少时间。
There's a time counter.
有一个计时器。
If it hits zero, you die.
如果达到零，则死亡。
Now, these are kind of annoying, because they're integers.
现在，这些有点烦人，因为它们是整数。
They could be kind of large.
它们可能很大。
So I'm going to say the score could be capital S big,
所以我要说分数可能是大写S，
and time could be capital T big.
时间可能是大资本。
So this'll be a pseudopolynomial algorithm.
因此，这将是一个伪多项式算法。
The number of configurations in total
总计配置数
here is the product of these things.
这是这些东西的产物。
It's exponential in w and h.
它在w和h中是指数的。
And then multiply by S and T. So that's
然后乘以S和T。
the number of configurations.
配置数量。
And that's also going to be our sub-problem.
这也将是我们的子问题。
I guess we should also write down
我想我们也应该写下来
where is the screen relative to the level.
屏幕相对于级别的位置在哪里。
OK, how far to the right have you gone?
好，你走到右边多远了？
That's another w.
那是另一个w。
That's not a big deal.
没什么大不了的。
OK, given this information, you know everything
好，有了这些信息，您就知道了一切
you need to know about playing from here on.
您需要从这里开始玩。
And the time counter's always going to keep ticking.
而且时间计数器总是在滴答作响。
So you can draw a graph of all configurations,
因此，您可以绘制所有配置的图表，
just enumerate all of these things.
只是列举所有这些事情。
It's this many of them.
就是这么多。
And then draw, for every configuration,
然后针对每种配置绘制
what are the possible things I can do?
我可以做些什么？
I could push this button.
我可以按一下此按钮。
I can push the A button, I can release the A button.
我可以按A按钮，也可以释放A按钮。
I can push the B button, I can release the B button.
我可以按B按钮，也可以释放B按钮。
I can push the up arrow.
我可以按向上箭头。
Those are all the things you could do.
这些就是您可以做的所有事情。
It's a constant number of choices.
这是一个不变的选择。
So each vertex will have constant out degree.
因此，每个顶点将具有恒定的出度。
If you did this, what configuration would I reach?
如果这样做，我将达到什么配置？
Just draw that whole graph.
只需绘制整个图形即可。
Do shortest paths.
做最短的路径。
Or dynamic programming, these are your sub-problems.
或动态编程，这些是您的子问题。
There are no suffixes here.
这里没有后缀。
These are your sub-problem.
这些是您的子问题。
And then you take a max, if you're
然后，如果您是
trying to maximize score or max if you're trying to maximize
尝试最大化分数或最大，如果您尝试最大化
time, minimize the time you use.
时间，尽量减少使用时间。
This is time remaining.
这是剩余时间。
And you can relate each sub-problem
您可以关联每个子问题
to a constant number of other sub-problems.
恒定数量的其他子问题。
So your running time will be this,
所以您的跑步时间将是这样，
because you only pay constant time per sub-problem.
因为您只为每个子问题支付固定时间。
And now you can solve Super Mario Brothers optimally,
现在您可以最佳解决超级马里奥兄弟了，
as long as your screen is not too big and as long
只要您的屏幕不太大且不长
as your scores and times don't get too big either,
因为你的分数和时间也不会太大
because we're only pseudopolynomial with respect
因为我们只是尊重的伪多项式
to S and T.
到S和T。
Questions?
有什么问题吗
All right.
好吧。
That's-- yeah?
是的-是吗？
AUDIENCE: So are we going to be trying
听众：那么我们将要尝试吗
to memoize all of these possible configurations?
记住所有这些可能的配置？
PROFESSOR: If you do the recursive version,
教授：如果您执行的是递归版本，
you will end up memoizing all of these configuration values.
您最终将记住所有这些配置值。
Well, anyone that's reachable from the initial state.
好吧，从初始状态可以到达的任何人。
Some configurations might not be reachable,
某些配置可能无法访问，
but the ones that are reachable you're
但是那些可及的你
going to start doing them.
要开始做他们。
When you finish doing them, you will memoize the result.
完成这些操作后，您将记住结果。